thelifefiles.com 2008-12-17

# » Privacy Policy » the.LIFE Files: Welcome to Exclusiveness

theLIFEfiles.com is a website based in New York state. We have created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy concerns. This privacy policy covers how we treat personal information that we collect and receive. By using this site, you do hereby warrant and represent that you have read, understand and agree to all terms and conditions stated herein. By using this site, you also represent and warrant that you have read, understand and agree to the terms and conditions of our Terms Of Use, which is incorporated herein by reference.

General  
We gather user information to provide you with a customized experience on our site. Your user information helps us tailor the content, services, goods and advertising to your current and future needs. For this reason, we may ask you to register or to provide personal information when you post comments, enter a contest, order products, subscribe to a newsletter and/or visit certain areas of our site. If you choose not to register you may not have access to areas that require personal identification.If you register with our site or purchase products from us, from time to time we may e-mail you with messages about our services or third party products and services we believe may be of interest to you, such as new products, features, services, special offers and updated information. The newsletters may contain code that enables our database to track your usage of the newsletters, including whether the e-mail was opened and/or what links (if any) were clicked. We will combine that information with other information we have about you and may use that information to improve your site experience and/or provide customized e-mail communications to you. In addition, if you register with our site or purchase products you may automatically receive e-mails confirming your registration and/or purchase and providing you with necessary information relating to the access or use of your registration and/or purchase. With the exception of the e-mails described in the preceding sentence which are necessary to provide customer support and deliver products and services to you, you may opt-out of receiving e-mail from us as described below.When you transmit information to our website, your IP address is logged and stored in a secure database. It is held as confidential. However, we may disclose your IP address if required to do so by law or if we have a good faith belief that disclosure is necessary to (1) comply with the law or with legal process served on us; (2) protect and defend our rights or property; or (3) act in an emergency to protect someone’s safety.We may also use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, prevent abuse of our systems or other site users, and to administer our Web site. Your IP address may also be used to gather aggregate demographic data and target advertisements accordingly.For reasons such as improving member experience and providing customized communications to our users, we may receive information about you from third party sources and our web logs and add it to the information that we have received from you. Web logs automatically record anything a web server sees, which may include e-mail addresses you enter into a form or pages viewed by a user at a particular IP address.Links and Information  
This site contains links to other sites. theLIFEfiles.com is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites and disclaims any liability for any damages that may result from the use of such sites. From time to time, Users have the opportunity to participate in special programs and will be able to opt in to programs that will transfer their information to other services. This will occur only with prior permission from the User. Unique identifiers are collected from Web site visitors to verify the user’s identity and for use as account numbers in our record system. theLIFEfiles.com expressly disclaims any liability that may arise from the provision of any User of any information whatsoever to this site. You, the User, do hereby agree to hold theLIFEfiles.com harmless from any liability that may arise from the provision of any information to this site. By using this site, you also represent and warrant that you have read, understand and agree to the terms stated in the Terms Of Use which is incorporated herein by reference. Pursuant to the Terms Of Use, you agree that all information provided to theLIFEfiles.com shall become the property of theLIFEfiles.com subject to any exclusions so stated herein.This site may also link to Websites that feature our trademarks and names along with trademarks and names of other companies. You should look at the privacy policy on that co-branded Website, as the co-branded Website may not be under our control. Applications you use or download from our site may contain third party digital rights management systems (”DRMS” which may allow for communication between your software and the third party and utilize security features (e.g., preventing distribution of or access to the applications in the event of unauthorized use). These DRMS are subject to their own license agreements and you agree that we shall not be responsible for any loss or damage of any sort relating to the use of the DRMS or your dealings with such third parties. The applications may also contain DRMS produced by us which allow for communication between the applications you use or download and our systems and which collect information describing your computer system in order to prevent illegal or unauthorized use of the applications.

Public Forums  
This site may create chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to its users. Any posting is governed by our Terms of Use. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information. You should take care to not use personal information in your bombs or other information that might be publicly available to other users. theLIFEfiles.com expressly disclaims any liability that may arise from the provision of any User of any information whatsoever to these forums. You, the User, do hereby agree to hold theLIFEfiles.com harmless from any liability that may arise from the provision of any information to these forums.

Security  
We have security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. Although we will exercise reasonable care in providing secure transmission of information between your computer and our servers, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information transmitted to us over the Internet and we accept no liability for any unintentional disclosure. theLIFEfiles.com is not responsible for any loss or misuse of any information you may submit to this site. You do hereby agree to hold theLIFEfiles.com harmless for any damages that may result from the use of this site. The submission of information to this site is done solely at the User’s own risk.

Cookies, and theLIFEfiles.com’s use thereof  
Your browser has options to accept, reject, or provide you with notice when a cookie is sent. A “cookie” is a small line of text that is stored with your Web browser for record-keeping purposes and to help us provide better service to you. We use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests and track your downloads and purchases from our site.We use companies to serve the advertisements on some of our pages. These companies and advertisers may place and access their cookies on your computer. Other companies’ use of their cookies is subject to their own privacy policies, not ours. We may use your information or allow advertisers or companies that serve advertisements access to your information to determine which advertisements you will see. This information may include your demographic information, geographic location, what content you access on our site, how you rate various content, language contained in your comments and other information. If you want to understand how and why an advertiser uses cookies, check the company’s site for their privacy statement. theLIFEfiles.com is not responsible for any issues that may arise regarding the Privacy Policies of any of its affiliates. By using this site, you do hereby agree to hold theLIFEfiles.com harmless from any claims and/or damages that may arise from the policies and/or practices (or lack thereof) of any of its affiliates and/or advertisers.

theLIFEfiles.com’s use of member information  
Two things drive theLIFEfiles.com’s decisions regarding the use of information collected from theLIFEfiles.com members: 1) improving user experience by offering personalized services and content, and 2) market research.theLIFEfiles.com may analyze information provided directly by you, or obtained through cookies or third parties to direct services and content based on your interests. theLIFEfiles.com reserves the right to collect market research data in order to generate sales to corporate clients. However, market research data may be used at the aggregate level to:-Improve the likelihood of a sale to a group of theLIFEfiles.com members  
-Increase the likelihood that a group’s experience on theLIFEfiles.com is relevant to its interests as a whole  
-Formulate group-level statistical models that are used to accomplish goal #2 (above).

theLIFEfiles.com’s market research may be collected in some of the following ways:  
-Through contests that are offered on the site; and,  
-Through general use of the site.

Information Sharing  
We will not share your personally identifiable information with third parties, aside from entities that perform services for us, such as fulfilling orders or processing payment, that either are bound to comply with our privacy policy or have privacy policies that protect your information unless you have “opted-in” to such sharing. If you have previously opted-in to such sharing under a prior privacy policy version, you are still considered to have opted-in under this privacy policy. As stated, and whether or not you have opted-in, we may use third parties to accept and process orders for merchandise and products, including software, and such third parties may get access to your personal information for the purposes of providing services or products to you on our behalf. In addition, if you opt-out, we may share that information with third parties who send e-mails on our behalf so that they do not e-mail you.However, we may disclose information you provide if required to do so by law or if we have a good faith belief that disclosure is necessary to (1) comply with the law or with legal process served on us; (2) protect and defend our rights or property; or (3) act in an emergency to protect someone’s safety.We may request demographic information from you (for example, your age, education level or household income) from time to time. We will not share that information in a manner that identifies you as an individual with any other entity, unless we let you know that at the time of collection or we have your permission. When we share demographic information with third parties, we will give them aggregate information only.

In the event that we acquired by another company, your personal information may be part of the assets transferred to the acquiring party.

Opt-Out  
If you provide us with your e-mail address, and do not opt-out of receiving e-mail from us, we may e-mail you with information, including information about selected third parties. If you do not want to receive information from us, you may decline to receive it (or “Opt-Out” either when you provide personal information to us or you may update your profile. You may also choose to Opt-Out from certain types of e-mail by following the unsubscribe instructions that appear on each newsletter. You may also contact us as provided below. Please note that there might be a brief delay between when you submit your request to opt-out and when it is processed and reflected in our systems; accordingly you might continue to receive e-mails from us for a few days after you unsubscribe. We maintain records of those users who opt-out of specific e-mail options so that we do not e-mail them with respect to those types of e-mails, and we may share this information with third parties who send e-mails on our behalf so that they do not e-mail you; this information may also be contained in web logs (see above).

Information logged by theLIFEfiles.com  
When you surf the Internet, your browser automatically transmits information to the sites you visit throughout every visit. Examples of such information include referral data (URL of the Web page you were on before coming to theLIFEfiles.com), IP address and your browser version. We collect this information to help improve our services and moderate the site. All the information that is automatically submitted by your browser is considered anonymous.theLIFEfiles.com also logs information you submit through registration, forms for optional programs, surveys and other entries, cookie data and communications transmitted through theLIFEfiles.com applications. Only authorized theLIFEfiles.com staff have access to your information in its entirety. Other employees may have access to bits and pieces of this information if it pertains to their job duties.To preserve the integrity of our databases, standard procedure calls for us to retain information submitted by members for an indefinite length of time. theLIFEfiles.com understands your submissions as consent to store all your information in one place for this indefinite length of time, if we so wish. If required by law, as is the case to comply with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA), we will nullify member information by erasing it from our database. We will also respond to written member requests to nullify account information. If you wish to make such a request, which requires that we verify your identity, or if you have any questions regarding this policy, contact theLIFEfiles.com using our contact form. Also, by using this site, you do hereby represent and warrant that you understand and agree that all information submitted by you to theLIFEfiles.com becomes the property of theLIFEfiles.com and may be used in the sole discretion of theLIFEfiles.com in accordance with this Privacy Policy and the Terms Of Use.

theLIFEfiles.com security of collected information  
theLIFEfiles.com makes every effort to ensure that your information is secure on its system. Only certain authorized theLIFEfiles.com employees can access this information if it’s relevant to their job duties. theLIFEfiles.com has staff dedicated to maintaining this Privacy Policy and other privacy initiatives, periodically reviewing Web security and making sure that every theLIFEfiles.com employee is aware of our security practices. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed 100% secure. As a result, theLIFEfiles.com cannot guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk. If you have any further questions on this issue, refer to the terms of the Terms Of Use. theLIFEfiles.com expressly disclaims any liability that may arise should any other individuals obtain the information you submit to this site.

With whom does theLIFEfiles.com share information?  
When you submit information to theLIFEfiles.com, it is generally collected, processed and maintained solely by us. Sometimes we may allow partner companies to collect information about members from us or directly from you (through their Web site). When theLIFEfiles.com is the source, it is usually so that we can provide a service with a partner. We choose to work with upstanding companies that will treat your information responsibly. But, since we don’t own these companies, we can’t speak for them on privacy issues. Before telling them about yourself, check out their privacy statements. If you are not satisfied with their information practices, you can choose to not use their service.Below is a summary of some of the situations in which theLIFEfiles.com might share information:

**Content Partners**  
Some theLIFEfiles.com content is “sponsored by” or “presented by” other companies. theLIFEfiles.com typically shares market research data (how the sponsorship performed, names of contest winners, etc.) collected on the site or via email surveys with these partners. This information is typically aggregate and not linked to specific users.

**Partner Sponsorships**  
Partners may sponsor promotions, contests and sweepstakes that require you to reveal details such as your name, address or phone number. Always check their privacy policy before revealing information about yourself. If you don’t want these sponsors to have your personal information, you can choose to not participate.When visitors come to theLIFEfiles.com, they may receive cookies from theLIFEfiles.com’s sponsors; this information is typically not shared with theLIFEfiles.com. This privacy statement does not address the information practices of our advertisers. You should read the privacy statements of all third-party sites, as their privacy policies may differ from theLIFEfiles.com’s.

Finally, theLIFEfiles.com reserves the right to disclose user information from both private and public areas of the site at our discretion to anyone or no one at all, if required by law or if given reason to believe, in our sole discretion, that someone is causing injury to or interference with the rights of theLIFEfiles.com members or the general public, or with theLIFEfiles.com’s rights of property. Please be advised, however, that all information submitted by you to theLIFEfiles.com becomes the property of theLIFEfiles.com. By submitting this information, you do hereby agree to allow theLIFEfiles.com to use such information at its sole discretion pursuant to the terms of the Terms Of Use.

Specifically, we may also share certain information about you with those of our vendors who are responsible for handling your account or performing other necessary services that you require. Although we may share sensitive financial information (i.e., credit card numbers, banking information), security information (e.g., account passwords) and personal communications (e.g., personal e-mail messages or message board postings) with such vendors where necessary and appropriate, we will not share such information with other third parties, except in response to formal requests (e.g., subpoena or court order) made in connection with litigation or arbitration proceedings directly relating to the services we provide.

Additionally, we may share the information stored on that database, as well as other information that is not of a sensitive nature, with carefully selected business partners, including those who offer services that complement those provided by us or which may otherwise be of interest to you. Finally, theLIFEfiles.com reserves the right to transfer, sell and/or distribute all information collected on its site for any purpose, including, but not limited to, for satisfaction of any debt or upon liquidation of the company should such a situation arise.

theLIFEfiles.com’s opt-in/out policy  
If you receive unsolicited email from a theLIFEfiles.com domain, please contact us using our contact form.

theLIFEfiles.com and the protection of children’s privacy  
theLIFEfiles.com is intended for people 18 or over. By using this site, you are agreeing to the terms in our Terms Of Use, which expressly affirms users must be aged 18 or over. Certain content on this site may be inappropriate for children. We are not responsible for the underage use of this website. If a parent believes that his or her child has submitted personal information to we, he or she can contact us via our contact form. We will promptly delete the information upon learning that it relates to a child under the age of 18. Please note that it is possible some of this information may remain archived in web logs and back-up archives after we delete the information from its active database.Our site is not directed to children under the age of 18. We respect the privacy of parents and children and are committed to complying with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA). On those areas of the sites that ask for age, we do not collect personal information from individuals who identify themselves as under the age of 13 except in those limited circumstances where we believe that such collection is permitted under COPPA.We believe that parents should supervise their children’s online activities and consider using parental control tools available from online services and software manufacturers that help provide a kid-friendly online environment. These tools can also prevent children from otherwise disclosing online their name, address and other personal information without parental permission.

Notification of Changes  
theLIFEfiles.com’s security and privacy policy are periodically reviewed and enhanced as necessary. This policy might change as theLIFEfiles.com updates and expands its services. theLIFEfiles.com encourages you to check the privacy policy on this site periodically. By using the site, you do hereby represent and warrant that you have read, understand and agree to all terms of this Privacy Policy and Terms Of Use. Each time you use the site, you agree to all terms set forth by theLIFEfiles.com in both its Privacy Policy and Terms Of Use and any other policies published by theLIFEfiles.com on the site. If you do not understand any of the terms or conditions of any of theLIFEfiles.com’s policies, send us an email via our online contact form.

How can I contact theLIFEfiles.com?  
If you have technical problems, questions, or other issues related to your use of theLIFEfiles.com, please contact us via our online contact form.theLIFEfiles.com’s staff will respond to all requests sent through email from members and parents interested in knowing more about what personal information is stored on the theLIFEfiles.com database, or have additional questions regarding privacy.

Contacting the Web Site  
If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you may contact us via our online contact form.

Other  
If a user elects to use our site for informing a friend about our site or particular features or content, we ask them for the friend’s name and e-mail address. We will automatically send the friend a one-time e-mail inviting them to visit our site. We store this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time e-mail.We maintain archives of our web logs, database, and other systems and information. Please note that it is possible some of this information may remain archived after we delete the information from its active database (see above regarding web logs). We maintain archives for disaster recovery, legal and other non-marketing purposes.>While this Privacy Statement expresses theLIFEfiles.com’s standards for maintenance of private data, it is not in a position to guarantee that the standards will always be met. There may be factors beyond theLIFEfiles.com’s control (e.g., “script kiddies”, “crackers and other malcontents”) that may result in disclosure of data. As a consequence, theLIFEfiles.com disclaims any warranties or representations relating to maintenance or nondisclosure of private information.

Binding Agreement  
Your use of our site, including any dispute concerning privacy, is subject to this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use. By using our Site, you are accepting the practices set out in this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Use. We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time by posting the changes on this page. Please check the revision date at the bottom of this page to determine if the statement has been modified since you last reviewed it. Your continued use of any portion of our Site following posting of the updated Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of the changes.

Last Revised March 1, 2008
